Michael Bogle

aoe4eva@gmail.com

Desired Position

I seek an employer that will use my skills to automate their current tasks. I desire a position that will help expand my current skills in scripting, server side data processing, and web development to create new tools for use and further refine current processes of the organization.

Summary of Qualifications

Well rounded Network and Systems Administrator with experience in LAN/WAN/WLAN data and telecommunications, security practices and technologies, as well as troubleshooting approaches. I am a heavy user of open source alternatives to supplement proprietary/closed source environments to ensure uptime, security, and overall health while achieving a lower Total Cost of Ownership (TCO). My goal is to never work too hard doing a repetitive task but work hard to automate a task. I write code to make my job easier, streamline my department's process, and make my colleagues' lives better by allowing them to work on tasks that really matter to them. My ultimate goal is to propel and accelerate the growth of my employer.

Accomplishments

- Writing a web application that helped digitize and automate the equipment ordering process for hiring managers.
- Create a whois to JSON wrapper to convert WHOIS queries to JSON format for use in a custom tool used by Network Engineers.
- Wrote a onboarding platform for new hires from scratch to speed up the hiring process. This standardized and streamlined the pipeline from Hiring Manager, HR, IT, to new hire.
- Got tired of creating hard passwords manually. This led me to create a shell script that did it for me which blossomed into https://pass.mjns.it.
- Automated tasks in Zendesk:
 - Filtering items from the Suspended Ticket Queue that may need attention but otherwise would be ignored.
 - Automatically verifying emails that match a list of valid domains.
- Using Node.js and Express.js to create a custom url rewriter/redirector instead of using
 the built in rewrite rules in Nginx. This really isn't an accomplishment since it was simple.
 I just thought it was cool.
- Built a provisioning portal that took the port speed and status from running network devices to assist the provisioning department in planning deployment of user services.
- I am always finding a way to automate tasks that would take myself and my colleagues more time to do manually. Which frees up their time and challenges me.

Education

Missouri Valley College 2004 - 2006

Discipline: Computer Sciences

GPA: 2.8

Degree: Not Obtained

Activities: Football (on Scholarship)

Broward College 2006 - 2008

Discipline: Computer Sciences

GPA: 2.8

Degree: Associates of the Arts

Certifications

CCNA (200-125) - CSCO11806465

CompTIA A+ - Verification Code: 5FBBJY92EHQES5GF

CompTIA Network+ - Verification Code: C07ZG2JJYKR1SST3
CompTIA Linux+ - Verification Code: JK4DV87L63FESTV7

Hurricane Electric IPv6 Certified: Sage Level - (Certificate Available)

Continued Education

Udemy.com

AJAX connection to MySQL PHP API - Laurence Svekis

Data Warehouse Concepts: Basic to Advanced concepts - Sid Inf

Learn API Technical Writing: JSON and XML for Writers - Peter Gruenbaum

Learn API Technical Writing 2: REST for Writers - Peter Gruenbaum

Cisco CCNA 200-125 – The Complete Guide to Getting Certified - Neil Anderson

Node.js API Masterclass With Express & MongoDB - Brad Traversy

Professional Experience

Hamilton Group Funding December 2019 - Present

Title: Tier 3 Support/Full Stack Developer

- Handled new issues in the zendesk ticket queue. As well as automate manual tasks.
- Worked with manger to plan out deployments of new procedures, technology, and services for the 400 plus users scattered throughout the US.
- Planned migration of local services to the Azure cloud.
- Introducing new network devices to improve company core and wireless network.
- Wrote various scripts to make deployment of computers faster in office and at remote locations.
 Scripts would retrieve information for Azure Intune and Autopilot as well as install our necessary company apps.
- Create an equipment ordering form for our various branches to use to order new equipment
 which also executed automated tasks. Such as ticket creation and email to vendor sales reps.
 Using Vanilla JavaScript on the front end, Node.js for server side execution, ExpressJS for API
 and web routes, with MongoDB (noSQL) as the storage backend.
- Create a new hire request form utilizing Node.js, ExpressJS, MongoDB, Vanilla JS again to create a more robust onboarding tool to replace the static PDF forms that were being used.
- Created various custom web apps to generate passwords, distribute software, and automate the creation of accounts.

MJ Network Solutions

2009 - 2019

Title: Lead Technician/Senior Consultant

- On-site and Remote troubleshooting.
- Onboarding and maintenance of MS Office 365 (Email, Sharepoint).
- MS Azure onboarding/migration and administration.
- Custom VoIP phone system design and deployment using cloud based servers.
- Recommendation and Implementation of System and Network upgrades.
- Data recovery using open source software.
- Desktop/Laptop Sales and service.
- Project management of large scale desktop and network deployments.
- Initial Active Directory/Exchange setup and ongoing maintenance.
- Installation and configuration of monitoring tools such as Cacti and Observium to assist with in depth troubleshooting.
- Wrote custom scripts for repeated tasks and designed APIs for data consumption.
- Wrote web applications for advertising, data entry, and status tracking.
- Wrote scripts that traversed various devices in a network to obtain routing and interface information that was used to identify customers and track Abuse Complaints for their IPs.

365 Datacenters

August 2011 – August 2020

Title: Network Operations (NetOps)

- WAN Level network troubleshooting of internal and remote customer connections.
- Trouble ticket creation and tracking of issues to ensure resolution.
- Monitoring and reporting issues of internal and customer resources using Observium, Orion Solarwinds and Nagios. Using these platforms to compile necessary metrics to assist with troubleshooting and resolution.
- Initial troubleshooting of Peering, MPLS, and Metro Ethernet connection issues for higher tiers of support.
- Linux hosting environment systems troubleshooting and resolution.

- Assist customers with virtual assets housed on the company's vmWare public cloud offering via vSphere fat client, vSphere Web UI, and later Embotics vCommander.
- Create custom web based tools for engineering staff from scratch with minimal direction from head network engineer. Our primary goal was full sale to configuration automation.
- Developed custom wrappers for functions like WHOIS that would make queries for routing information and convert the output to JSON that can be later parsed.
- Create custom dashboards with the amCharts 4 charting library. Data visualized/charted comes
 from a custom Node.js script that pulls data from an Observium (network monitoring and billing
 system) MySQL table and ships it as JSON object to a custom API that stores data in MongoDB.
- Where necessary I made custom bash and Node.js scripts to collect and move data where needed for a task on the server/backend side that was later used by various libraries and custom Java Script functions on the front end.

DeRose Technologies Inc. 2008 – 2010

Title: Technician/Consultant

- On-site and Remote troubleshooting.
- Disaster Recovery and backup administration.
- Research and Development of new software and hardware for possible use in customer environments.
- Part of the design, implementation, and oversight team in charge of retrofitting a customer's new
 office location. Coordinating cabling, equipment purchases and configuration, relocation, and
 ongoing maintenance and support in the new location.

Coconut Consulting 2007 – 2012

Title: Outside Network Consultant

- VPN design and troubleshooting.
- Initial install of Zimbra Collaboration Suite email server.
- Linux server consulting.
- Remote Network and Systems troubleshooting.

Reliant Medical 2007 - 2008

Title: Systems and Network Administrator

- Network overhaul. Adding redundant firewalls w/ IDS/IPS, switch and NIC upgrades to gigabit speeds.
- Upgrades in Active Directory environments from single server to multi server and 2003 to 2008.
 As well as fully utilizing DNS integrated with AD.

Technical Skills/Knowledge

Cloud: Private Cloud using VmWare, MS Azure, AWS, Office 365

Software: Bacula, Symantec Backup Exec, Squid, Apache, NGINX, MySQL,

MongoDB, MS Office

Hardware: Dell, Cisco, HP, Supermicro, Sun/Oracle, Rasperry Pi

Operating Systems: Windows 2000 - 2016, Debian, Ubuntu. Fedora, CentOS, SuSE,

Proxmox, VMware

Networking: Cisco/Dell/Netgear/D-Link/Sonicwall/Open Source Routers, Switches,

and Firewalls. VLAN, Trunking, Jumbo Frames, LACP, Routing Basics

Monitoring Systems: Orion Solarwinds, Cacti, OpenNMS, Zabbix, Observium

Coding: Bash Scripting, PHP, Node.js, jQuery, Vue, HTML, Puppeteer

Other: ZFS, GlusterFS

References

James Ashton (Manager 365DC) - 706-458-0234 Damien Martin - 954-716-2607 - Former Co-Worker Cecil - CEO - Coconut Consulting - 954-599-7722 - Colleague

My Software

Github Repositories:

https://github.com/mjnshosting https://github.com/treestarsystems

Bash Scripts:

https://github.com/treestarsystems/growBox-Seed https://github.com/mjnshosting/ip-block-search https://github.com/mjnshosting/RokuController

Node.js Projects:

https://github.com/treestarsystems/growBox-Stem https://github.com/treestarsystems/postReceive

Web Apps:

https://hire.hamiltonhomeloans.com/ (Node.js + VanillaJS)
https://www.thegrowboxproject.com/ (Node.js + VanillaJS + jQuery)
https://pass.mins.it/ (jQuery)

Example of Documentation:

https://treestarsystems.atlassian.net/wiki/spacedirectory/view.action